

427 Cope Drive

Fullstack Software Engineer

A Canadian permanent resident who is a tech enthusiast. Full-stack developer with 5+ years of experience in React, React Native, and Javascript. Specialized in building and maintaining web and mobile applications for thousands of users, focusing on application security, responsiveness, and scalability. A team player with strong communication skills, committed to creating effective solutions that align with business needs. Strong proficiency with JavaScript and TypeScript as a language and ReactJS, VueJs, NextJs, NestJs as frameworks.

Interested in front-end and/or mobile development roles at any level.

Professional Experience

Fullstack Software Engineer OnePort 365, Lagos, Lagos | February 2021 - Present

- Co-Led a cross-functional team to develop West Africa's first digital freight forwarding management application, serving 10,000+ clients.
- Developed a comprehensive booking system for freight forwarding using Typescript for the front end development, allowing customers to select shipment types (Import/ Export) and desired services including Ocean Freight, Haulage, Air Freight, Custom Brokerage and Warehousing.
- Using NodeJs primarily, while using ExpressJS for some of the work, I completed the devlopment of the booking system's backend
- Responsible for the website's database management, with MongoDB as a tool to save data being sent from the client-side of the web application.
- For cloud management, I initially launched web application using Heroku as deployment tool prior to migrating to the use of Digital Ocean due to management conflict between GitHub and Heroku complicating full deployment of web applications using Heroku.
- Using ReactJS, I developed a container tracking system and interactive map view to monitor the location of goods by integrating with google maps API, improving customer experience and satisfaction.
- Using ReactJS, I designed an admin dashboard to monitor key company metrics, including total numbers of customers, shipments, containers, and bookings, facilitating better operational oversight.
- Managed the deployment and maintenance of MongoDB clusters, ensuring high availability of the OnePort 365 web application which resulted in a 30% reduction in downtime.
- Optimized MongoDB database performance through indexing strategies and query optimization, improving query response times by 40%.
- Implemented a feature to view and compare freight forwarding rates and process charged by different companies, enhancing cost transparency for users with ReactJS.
- Configured monitoring and alerting systems for MongoDB using a tool called Prometheus, significantly reducing incident response times.
- Integrated with Ascent a third party tracking agency to monitor hardware tracking devices in freight containers, displaying real-time locations on an integrated map for enhanced customer transparency.
- Integrated a global map view for tracking container location with functionality to filter between import and export shipments.
- Implemented an integrated invoicing feature and seamlessly integrated with QuickBooks, enhancing financial management capabilities and streamlining finance operations for the team.
- Developed a country-specific service display on the landing page, tailored for target marketing including, Ghana, Kenya and Nigeria, optimizing user experience and market engagement
- Designed, created, and managed RESTful APIs with Node.js, Express.js, and GraphQL. Incorporating CRUD operations, authentication, authorization, and validation mechanisms into the API.
- Utilizing MongoDB for data storage, including schema design, query composition, and database performance enhancements, resulting in a 60% improvement in performance.
- Streamlined development processes and improved team productivity by 20% while reducing project delivery time by 15% as a key contributor within an agile team.
- Championed the setup and configuration of a React based application, accurately translating complex designs into functional interfaces, architecting optimized database schemas, and crafting robust API endpoints.

Software Engineer Tunga, Amsterdam | April 2023 - Present

- Utilized React Native to design and implement responsive, high-performance user interfaces for a mobile application called Fanect, ensuring a seamless user experience across both iOS and Android platforms.
- Collaborated with UX/UI designers to translate wireframes and mockups into interactive and visually appealing mobile app screens, focusing on user engagement and accessibility
- Employed React to build and enhance the admin dashboard, creating intuitive and efficient management tools for administrators to monitor and manage user activities, content, and analytics
- Implementing state management solutions using Redux and Context API to maintain application state consistency and improve data handling efficiency across different components.
- Managed deployment processes using Cloudways and AWS, ensuring reliable and scalable hosting solutions for both the mobile application. This included setting up continuous integration and continuous deployment (CI/CD) pipelines, monitoring server performance, and optimizing resource usage to ensure high availability and low latency.
- Utilized Firebase to ensure secure and scalable delivery of the admin dashboard application updates and real-time database management for user-generated content.

Frontend Software Developer LeniLabs, Lagos, Lagos | December 2019 - January 2022

- Implemented a highly developed GraphQL APIs for a high-traffic e-commerce web applications like (https://www.artgidi.com/), improving data retrieval efficiency by 30% as well as building GraphQL queries and mutations to streamline data access, resulting in a 25% reduction in backend response times.
- Deployed and developed scalable GraphQL schemas for a SaaS application (https://www.mayfairdesignstudio.ng/), enhancing client-side data fetching and reducing payload sizes by 20%
- Created intuitive admin dashboards for e-commerce and e-Library applications, improving user management and data analysis, resulting in a 30% boost in productivity and data-driven decision-making.
- Crafted professional and responsive websites for corporate firms, showcasing their brand identity and driving online presence, resulting in a 40% increase in website traffic and user engagement.
- Engineered a web application for dispatch operations, integrating Google Maps for precise geolocation services, optimizing delivery efficiency by 25% and reducing transportation costs by 15%.
- Solicited and incorporated feedback from colleagues to streamline the software development life cycle, resulting in a 20% reduction in development time and improved team efficiency.
- Tested software to ensure responsiveness and efficiency before sending it to Quality assurance team to ease their stress.
- Troubleshooting, debugging and making upgrades to the software Created security and data protection settings
- Researched and evaluated variety of interactive media software products.
- Conducted tests and performed security and quality controls on built websites.

Education

Bsc in Process Engineering University of Lagos, Lagos, Nigeria | January 2014 - January 2019

Diploma in Web Development Lighthouse Labs, Toronto | January 2024 - March 2024 Learned how to build and style websites and landing pages using HTML, CSS & JavaScript.

Key Skills

- Javascript
- HTML & CSS
- React JS
- React Native
- Redux
- Node JS
- TypeScript
- Express JS

- Next JS
- Vue JS
- GraphQL
- MongoDB
- Firebase
- Heroku
- AWS
- Digital Ocean
- Clowdways
- kubernetes
- React Query
- Laravel

Volunteering

Programming for Beginners (Yaba, Alagomeji) | January 2021 - June 2021

A group of programmers teaching primary and secondary school students the opportunities in tech, and the benefits of being technically strong in order to succeed in software engineering and design

Leap Nigeria Foundation (Lekki Lagos) | November 2021 - February 2022

A society that brings together engineering and science graduates from different fields to discuss technical advancements, and engage in discussions on requirements for success in the current job market.